翻譯：灰灰是菇涼  面條打包子  Michael  非燕  王小麥  那時花開
翻譯：靜靜的木頭  莎友友  壹不貳   時間軸：Sagelibra  Sweet寶寶
超感警探
第六季
第七集
校對&后期：灰灰是菇涼   總監：灰灰是菇涼
《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
她說血腥約翰左肩膀有個紋身
She told me Red John has a tattoo on his left shoulder--
三個點
three dots.
這是我的籌碼
That's my leverage.
把五名疑犯同時
Gather all five suspects together
集合到一個地方
at the same place, same time,
然后再檢查是否有紋身
and then start checking for the tattoo.
如何才能做到呢
How do we do that?
-周四晚上八點見面  -好吧
- Meet me at 8:00 on Thursday night. - Fine.
周四晚上八點
Thursday night at 8:00.
-我需要你的幫助  -沒問題
- I'll need your help. - Well, then you've got it.
你如果不去  他就會認為你是血腥約翰
If you don't show up, he will assume you're Red John.
我如果去了  你和簡
If I do this, will you and Jane drop
就不會再懷疑我是血腥約翰了嗎
the whole that "I'm Red John" business?
以后絕對不會了
For once and for all.
你真的確定了嗎
You really think you've got him?
-是的  -此案結束的時候我要在場
- I do. - I want to be there when you end this.
就等您這句話呢
I was hoping you'd say that.
血腥約翰
Red John.
今晚我若能去見你
Nothing would give me more pleasure
那是再高興不過了
than to be with you there tonight.
血腥約翰  有個紋身
Red john... has a tattoo.
左臂上有三個點  就在肩膀上
Three dots on his left arm. On the shoulder.
你們都得
And you all...
給我看
are gonna show me...
立刻動手
Now.
開始脫吧  快
Let's go. Come on.
對了  脫掉
That's it. Take it off.
太荒唐了
Nonsense.
很好
Very good.
不是你想的那樣
It's not what you think.
你弄錯了
You got it wrong.
我不是血腥約翰
I'm not Red John.
派翠克  等等  派翠克
Patrick, wait. Patrick!
看  這邊
Look... here.
看
Look.
站起來
On your feet.
到他們倆那邊去
Over with those two.
你們別動
You stay there.
好了  你們三個
Okay, you three...
到墻邊站著  快
Over against that wall-- now.
等等  不要
Wait! No!
快叫消防部門和急救人員過來
Call the fire department and E.M.Ts.
告訴他們這里有多人傷亡
Let them know that there's multiple casualties,
警戒線拉起來
and set up a perimeter.
是的  長官
Yes, ma'am.
-把你的手電筒給我  我進去  -給你
- Give me your flashlight. I-I'm going in. - Here you go.
簡
Jane.
Jane?
史密斯探員
Agent Smith.
史密斯探員  我是特蕾莎·里斯本
Agent Smith, it's Teresa Lisbon.
-你沒事吧  -發生了什么事
- Are you okay? - What happened?
這里剛剛發生了爆炸  急救人員已經在路上了
There was an explosion. The E.M.Ts are on their way.
他們會救治你
They're gonna help you.
-不許動  -什么
- Don't move! - What?
把手舉起來
Put your hands in the air,
不然我就開槍了  快
or I'll shoot! Do it!
聽著  我不明白你在說什么
Okay, listen, I don't know what you're talking about.
你明顯搞錯了
You're clearly making a big mistake.
史密斯往哪邊走了
Which way did Smith go?
我的天哪  里斯本
Oh, my god, Lisbon.
頭兒  我們必須得找到史密斯  他是血腥約翰
Boss? We have to find Smith. He's Red John.
我去找人幫忙
Ah... I'll get help.
簡
Jane?
你能聽到我講話嗎
Can you hear me?
簡  快醒醒
Jane? Come on.
你還好吧
You okay?
還好
I'm fine.
醫生說簡的情況穩定
The doctors say Jane's stable.
沒受什么重傷
There's no major trauma or anything.
他只是醒不過來
He's just not awake.
現場發現了三個人的殘骸
They found the remains of three people.
化驗確認是布萊特·斯特爾斯  雷·哈弗內
Positive I.Ds for Bret Stiles, Ray Haffner,
和托馬斯·麥卡利斯特的
and Thomas McAllister.
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
我以為核攻擊都干不掉布萊特·斯特爾斯呢
I would think Bret Stiles would survive a nuclear attack.
尸體都被燒焦了
The bodies are all burnt to a crisp,
但鑒證科還是提取出了DNA
but the crime techs did spot D.N.A. tests.
驗尸官那邊將結果與醫療記錄進行比對
Coroner's office checked it against medical records.
已確認三位死者正是
Stiles, Haffner, and McAllister
斯特爾斯  哈弗內和麥卡利斯特
are all positively dead.
那史密斯呢  有人看到他嗎
Uh, what about Smith? Any sightings?
還沒  瑞斯比和范佩爾正在查
Not yet. Rigsby and Van Pelt are on it.
長官
Sir?
就知道在這兒能找到你
Ah, thought I might find you here.
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
沒事  不過我確實得喝杯咖啡
Uh, I'm fine. I could use a cup of coffee, actually.
你能幫我去買一杯嗎
Would you go and get me one?
我們馬上要開始聯合追捕史密斯了
We're just about to coordinate the manhunt for Smith.
那你該趕快去抓他
Well, you should just go and get him.
我更想待在這里  長官
Well, I'd like to stay here, sir.
-你是...  -周和其他組員應付得來
- Well, are... - Cho and the team... they can handle it.
你是要拒絕執行我的命令嗎
Are you refusing a direct order?
不是的
Well, no.
我只是想在這里陪他
No, I just want to stay here with him.
你給我聽清楚了
Wh-why don't you listen a little more closely?
我命令你現在馬上離開
I am ordering you to get out there,
帶領你的組員一起去抓捕史密斯
put your team together, and get Smith.
簡  簡  那個呼叫按鈕在哪呢
Jane? Jane? Where's the damn call button?
我去叫護士
I'll--I'll get the nurse.
簡
Jane.
頭兒
Hey, boss.
我們現在認為  是血腥約翰帶去的炸彈
Our working theory is that Red John brought in the bomb
想要殺死簡和其他嫌犯
to kill Jane and the other suspects.
好吧  但怎么布下的
Okay, but how?
可能是血腥約翰隨身偷偷帶進去的
Chances are, Red John snuck the bomb in on his person.
犯罪現場小組從墻上發現了
Crime techs have pulled fragments of the bomb casings
炸彈外殼的碎片  碎片非常小
from the walls-- very small fragments.
這說明火藥密度高  威力很大
This tells us that the explosive was dense, high-powered.
那肯定不是自制的
That doesn't sound homemade.
沒錯  我猜是軍用級別的
No. Military grade's my bet,
這就說明我們能夠追蹤到來源
which means it could be traceable.
這些是最有可能的來源
These are the most likely sources.
查查看最近他們中
Check for any recent thefts
有誰曾報告丟失過炸藥
of missing explosives from any of them.
好的  馬上去
All right, will do.
-有線索了嗎  -是的
- Got something? - Yeah.
里斯本在史密斯逃走前曾擊中過他
Lisbon wounded Smith before he escaped.
他是帶著槍傷在四處逃竄
He's walking around with a bullet.
醫院看到槍傷必須向警方報備
Well, hospitals have to declare gunshot wounds,
所以他不能去看急診
so he can't go to an E.R.
沒錯  他需要一個不會聲張的醫生
Right, so he needs a doctor who'll keep quiet.
史密斯一直在薩克拉門托工作
Smith's based here in Sacramento,
我查了一下全市他負責過的案件
so I looked into some of his old cases around town.
他所在的緝毒小組
He was part of a task force
去年在薩克拉門托市南部
that arrested Dr. Alek Lavrov
抓捕過阿列克·拉夫羅夫醫生
last year in south Sac.
一個非法開具奧施康定[強力止痛藥]處方的醫生
A Dr. Feelgood writing illegal oxycontin scripts.
Dr. Feelgood指的是常給病人開出興奮劑等安慰性藥方的醫生
-然后呢  -案子審判不順利
- So? - So the case went bad,
證物丟失  拉夫羅夫被無罪釋放
evidence was lost, and Lavrov walked.
所以史密斯很清楚在哪能找到一位
So Smith knows exactly where to find a doctor
不會報警的醫生
who won't talk to the cops.
很好  我們馬上去查
Great, let's go check it out.
不是你想的那樣
It's not what you think.
我不是血腥約翰
I'm not Red John.
派翠克  等等  看
Patrick, wait. Look.
歡迎回來
Welcome back.
里斯本
Lisbon.
你家里發生了爆炸
There was an explosion at your house.
我昏迷多久了
How long have I been out?
十二個小時
12 hours.
里德·史密斯是血腥約翰
Reede Smith is Red John.
我看到他肩膀上的紋身了
I saw the tattoo on his shoulder.
不只他有
He's not the only one.
麥卡利斯特身上也有
McAllister has one, too.
他已經死了  斯特爾斯和哈弗內也死了
He's dead. So are Stiles and Haffner.
-還有伯特侖  -伯特侖
- And Bertram. - Bertram?
他也有那個紋身
He has the tattoo as well.
我的天
Oh, my God.
他剛才還在這
He was just here.
他剛才就站在你身邊
He was standing over you.
他  他還一直想讓我離開
He--he was trying to get me to leave.
他是要殺了你
He was gonna kill you.
-我的衣服呢  -別著急  好嗎
- Where are my clothes? - Slow down, okay?
我沒事  我們沒有時間了
No, it's okay. We don't have time.
簡  簡
Jane. Jane.
我的衣服呢
Where are my clothes?
我是特蕾莎·里斯本
This is Teresa Lisbon.
在全州境內發出里德·史密斯
Put out a statewide alert for the apprehension
和蓋爾·伯特侖的通緝令
of Reede Smith and Gail Bertram.
沒錯  就是伯特侖局長
Yes, Director Bertram.
接近時務必小心
Approach with caution.
他們持有武器  十分危險
They're considered armed and dangerous.
他們其中一個就是血腥約翰
One of them is Red John.
伊凡·拉夫羅夫醫生診所
今日停業
請趕快離開  女士  警察辦案
Move along, ma'am. Police business.
天啊
Ah, my God!
是的
Yes.
子彈還在你體內
The bullet is still inside you.
別廢話了  趕緊取出來
No crap! Get it out!
會很疼的
This is going to hurt.
你確定不吃點止疼藥
Are you sure you won't take something for the pain?
不吃
No...
不吃  我要保持警覺
No. I gotta stay sharp.
那就隨你吧
As you like.
天啊
God!
老虎  老虎
Tiger, tiger.
史密斯在這
Smith in there?
是的  他快喊破喉嚨了
Yeah. He's screaming his head off.
他不會成為麻煩的  你打算怎么做
He won't be a problem. How you wanna do it?
我剛從加調局得到消息
I just got word from inside CBI.
有幾個探員正要來這里找史密斯
Couple of agents are coming here right now looking for Smith.
-那我們該怎么辦  -趕緊了事
- So what do we do? - We hurry.
你進去搞定他  加調局的人來了我拖住他們
You go get him. I'll run interference if CBI shows.
好的
You got it.
從后面把他帶出去  在那干掉他
Take him out the back. Do it there.
-他逼我這么做的  我是無辜的  -閉嘴
- He made me do this. I'm innocent. - Shut up.
只要他一走我就會報警的
I would have called the police as soon as he left.
-我不想惹麻煩  -閉嘴
- I don't want any trouble! - Quiet!
你也是組織的人
You association?
老虎  老虎  你為什么不給我們打電話
Tiger, tiger. Why didn't you call us?
說來真怪  因為我不相信你們
Funnily enough, I got trust issues.
你要信任你的朋友
Hey, you gotta trust your friends.
我是來幫你的  你能走路嗎
I'm here to help you. Can you walk?
我得給他縫好  不然會失血的
I need to sew him up. He'll bleed.
我能走路
Ah... I can walk.
你是科德羅警探  對吧
Detective Cordero, right?
瑞斯比探員
Agent Rigsby.
你好
How are ya?
他是薩城警局的  負責柯克蘭槍擊案
He's, uh, Sac P.D. worked the Kirkland shooting.
這位是格蕾斯·范佩爾探員
This is Agent Grace Van Pelt.
你們怎么來薩城南部了
What brings you to South Sac?
我們跟一條線索過來抓里德·史密斯
We're chasing up a lead on Reede-- Reede Smith.
也就是  血腥約翰
AKA, Red John.
看來我們快你們一步
Looks like we beat you to the punch.
我的人已經進去抓他了
One of my guys is in there getting him right now.
需要我們看住后面嗎
You want us to cover the back?
-不用  我們能搞定  -你確定
- No. No, we got it. - You sure?
雖然我們不是加調局的  但是我們也是警察
Hey, we might not be CBI, but we know what we're doing.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
什么事
Yep?
瑞斯比  你在哪里
Rigsby, where are you?
在醫生辦公室外面  史密斯好像在里面
Outside the doctor's office. Looks like Smith's inside.
有警察在你身邊嗎
Are there policemen with you?
有  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
好的  你仔細聽清楚
Okay, listen carefully.
不要相信任何一名執法人員
Do not trust anyone in law enforcement.
誰也不能相信  明白嗎
Anyone at all. Do you understand?
好的
You got it.
謝了
Thanks.
我們去后面四周看看
Let's, uh, go take a look around back.
等等
Wait a minute.
你們去哪里
Where are you going?
車就在這邊
Car's back this way.
一切都安排好了
Everything's taken care of.
在附近有個安全屋  干凈衣服  一名醫生
We got a safe house nearby, fresh clothes, a doctor...
出城的路線也準備好了
A trip out of town.
安全屋
A safe house, huh?
我也對某個人說過一次
You know, I said that to someone once.
是嗎  后來呢
Yeah? What happened after that?
我朝他后背開了六槍
I shot him six times in the back.
乖乖就范吧
Come on.
該死
Damn it.
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
站住
Stop!
-你沒事吧  -沒事  你還好吧
- You all right? - Yeah! You good?
嗯
Yeah.
史密斯趁亂逃走了
Smith got away during the fight.
那個警探也是
So did the detective.
頭兒  他們想殺史密斯和我們  這是為什么
Boss, they were trying to kill Smith and us. Why?
-我不知道  -看看他的肩膀
- I don't know. - Check the shoulder.
-什么  -讓他看看左肩
- What? - Ask him to check the left shoulder.
讓瑞斯比把他襯衣脫了看他的肩膀
Have Rigsby take his shirt off and look at his shoulder.
里斯本想讓你看他的左肩
Lisbon wants you to check his left shoulder.
怎么回事
What the hell?
有  他肩上有那個紋身
He's got it. He's got the tattoo.
頭兒  這是怎么了
Boss, what's happening?
好  把他帶回局里
All right, bring him in
別讓任何人接近他
and don't let anybody else get to him.
帶回去
Bring him in.
查到襲擊你們的警察身份了嗎
What do we know about the cop who attacked you?
這是我們抓到的那個  保羅·魏海根警官
This is the one we caught. Officer Paul Wiehagen.
當警察六年  模范警察
Six years on the force. Exemplary record,
受過幾次表彰  沒紀律問題
a couple of commendations, no real discipline problems.
那另一個  科德羅警探呢
What about the other one-- Detective Cordero?
打電話問了他隊長
Put a call in to his captain.
說他一小時前請了病假
Said he called in sick an hour ago.
還是沒查到伯特侖的行蹤
And still no sign of Bertram.
那就著重調查我們抓到的這個
Let's focus on the one we do have.
或許簡會弄清真相
Maybe Jane will figure it out.
有人派你殺里德·史密斯嗎
Did someone send you to kill Reede Smith?
無可奉告
I got nothing to say.
你為什么要殺他
Why were you gonna murder him?
那紋身是怎么回事  有什么意義
What about the tattoo? What's it mean?
你不善言辭  我懂
You're not a big talker. I get it.
禍從口出嘛
Loose lips sink ships and all that.
壞消息是  你的表情控制得不夠好
The bad news is, you have a lousy poker face.
所以我們要玩個你演我猜的小游戲
So we're gonna play a little game of show-and-tell.
我告訴你些事
I'm gonna tell you something,
你用表情告訴我
and you're gonna show me with your face
是對是錯
whether I'm right or not.
有意思嗎
That sound fun?
你偷過東西嗎
You ever steal anything?
你背著女友偷腥過嗎
Did you ever cheat on your girlfriend?
打過她嗎
Hit her?
你喜歡施暴嗎
Do you like causing pain?
我從沒打過女人
I never hit a woman in my life.
你是一個由警察和其他政府官員
Do you belong to a secret organization of cops
組成的秘密組織成員嗎
and other government officials?
是的
Yes.
你為維護那個組織的利益犯過罪
You've committed crimes on behalf of that organization before.
對嗎
Right?
史密斯探員也是組織成員
Agent Smith is a member also...
對嗎
Right?
組織派你去那個診所殺他
The organization sent you to the doctor's office to kill him,
對嗎
right?
加調局局長蓋爾·伯特侖也是組織成員
CBI director Gail Bertram is also a member.
你不知道
You don't know.
等級太低了對吧
Too low on the totem pole, huh?
里德·史密斯探員是血腥約翰
Agent Reede Smith is Red John.
不知道
Don't know.
蓋爾·伯特侖是血腥約翰
Gail Bertram's Red John.
不知道
Don't know.
你肩上的紋身是組織成員的標志
That tattoo on your shoulder is the membership sign.
我不知道你在說什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
又對了
Right again.
還有個暗號
There's a password, too--
是你們成員間用來識別身份
Something you say as a greeting or a...
和求救的
distress signal.
"老虎  老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
從我腦子里滾出去
Get out of my head.
一個腐敗警察的秘密組織
A secret society of dirty cops.
血腥約翰是成員之一
And Red John's a member.
帕特里奇
Partridge.
他死之前對我說了"老虎  老虎"
He said "tiger, tiger" to me right before he died.
對  沒錯
Hmm. Yes. Yes.
他在求救
He was asking for help
寄希望于你也是成員之一
in the hopes that you were a member.
但是如果他也有紋身
But if he had a tattoo,
驗尸報告里應該有
it would have been in the autopsy report.
不能相信什么報告
Well, you can't trust a file.
要親眼看到才行
We have to see it.
我會讓周去檢查尸體
I'll have Cho track down the body.
但是很有可能帕特里奇已經下葬了
But Partridge could be buried by now.
那就讓周帶上鏟子
Well, have Cho bring a shovel.
我們的人在找史密斯  伯特侖在外逃中
The team's looking for Smith, Bertram's on the run.
到底誰是血腥約翰
So who's Red John?
是伯特侖還是史密斯
Is it Bertram or Smith?
我要看著他們的眼睛才能確定
I need to look them both in the eye.
驗尸官兩天前把尸體送過來的
Yeah, the coroner released his body, like, two days ago.
-謀殺案被害人是吧  -是的
- Murder victim, huh? - Yeah.
我猜就是  所以才會一直留著他
I figured. That's why we held him for so long.
幸好你今天來了
Good thing you got here today.
明天就什么都看不到了
Tomorrow there won't be much left of him to look at.
在這兒
Here we go.
布雷特·帕特里奇
Brett Partridge.
幫把手
Give me a hand, huh?
你的了
He's all yours.
把刀給我
Give me your knife.
燒之前都會給他們穿上好衣服
They dress 'em before we burn 'em.
我也不知道為什么
Don't ask me why.
周發了張照片過來
Cho sent a picture.
說明什么
What does it mean?
你覺得這說明什么
What do you think it means?
史密斯處理好了么
What happened with Smith?
我們差點就在診所那里解決他了
We almost got him at his doctor's office.
加調局的人來了
That CBI team showed up.
史密斯跑了
Smith's in the wind.
他可真會跑
That's a good place to be.
我有點事要處理
I've got some business in here,
在這兒等我
so wait for me.
謝謝  托馬斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Thomas.
您很久沒來了
We haven't seen you for a while.
很高興見到你
Yeah. It's nice to see you.
史密斯現在可能在任何地方
Smith could be anywhere by now.
我試著追蹤他手機上全球定位信號
I tried to trace the G.P.S. signal on his cell phone.
已經關閉好幾個小時了
It's been dead for hours.
像他這樣的腐敗聯調局警察一定會有一次性手機
A dirty F.B.I. cop like him has to have a burner.
拉夫羅夫醫生說他還沒縫合史密斯的傷口
Dr. Lavrov says he didn't get the chance to sew Smith up.
他現在還帶著槍傷四處走動
He's still walking around with a bullet wound.
那么不管他在哪兒  情況一定不好
So he's in a bad way wherever he is.
最終一定會被人發現的
He'll get picked up by someone eventually.
是啊  但是發現他的警察
Yeah, but any cop who finds him...
太可怕了  我們誰都不能信
This is scary. We can't trust anyone.
是啊
Nope.
范佩爾探員
Agent Van Pelt.
你得幫幫我
You gotta help me.
史密斯探員
Agent Smith.
他們會殺了我的
They're gonna kill me.
我要自首
I wanna surrender.
你在哪兒
Where are you?
第十八大道
在市中心  給周打電話  他應該在附近
Downtown. Call Cho. He should be close.
知道了  我們這就來
Okay, we're on our way.
史密斯聯系加調局了
Smith reached out to CBI.
他用了組織給他的一次性手機
He used the burner the association gave him.
我們監聽了那部手機
We were listening.
他要自首
He's turning himself in.
沒錯  叛徒
Yeah. Rat.
加調局的人去接他了
That CBI team is on its way to get him now.
這可不行  他在哪兒
Well, we can't have that. Where is he?
離這兒不遠的小巷子里  我們運氣很不錯
He's in an alley not too far from here. Our good luck.
他認識你嗎
Does he know who you are?
不認識  在診所那兒他沒看見我
Nah, he didn't see me at the doctor's office.
好  你現在就是加調局探員了
All right. You are now a CBI agent.
要一起去嗎  說不定挺好玩兒的
You want to come along? Could be fun.
不去了  我還有別的事要處理
No. I have some other business to take care of.
-到時再碰頭吧  -行
- We'll meet up later. - You got it.
這次別失手了  行嗎
Can you get it right this time?
是  長官
Yes, sir!
里德·史密斯探員
Agent Reede Smith?
在嗎  范佩爾探員派我來的
You out there? Agent Van Pelt sent me.
你是誰
Who are you?
奧斯卡·科德羅探員  加調局的
Agent Oscar Cordero, CBI.
我來接你回去
I'm here to take you in.
你得保證我安全
You gotta keep me safe.
他們無處不在
They're everywhere.
沒錯
Yeah.
我們無處不在
We are.
天吶
God...
到車尾去
Back of the car now.
你不會真以為你能逃脫得了吧
You didn't really think you could get away from us, did you?
你懂事的  幫個忙  自己爬后備箱里去吧
You're a big boy. Do me a favor and get in the trunk yourself.
再讓我歇會兒  行嗎
Just give me a second, will you?
到后備箱里去歇吧
You'll have a second in the trunk.
別逼我動手
Now don't make me do painful things to you.
上車
Get in the car!
我有個條件  我要求完全豁免權
I'm gonna need a deal. Full immunity.
除非你們放過我  否則我一個字都不會說的
I'm not saying a word unless I can walk.
那你走吧
So walk.
什么
What?
站起來走吧
Get up off your ass and walk.
不過但愿你能在你的朋友追上你之前
But, hey, good luck getting out of the building
走出這棟大樓
before your friends catch up with you.
只要你坦白我們所要的信息
If you tell us everything we need to know,
我保證把你安排在遠離加州的
I promise we will put you in a federal prison
聯邦監獄
far away from California.
保證你安全
Someplace that you'll be safe.
五年前  我傷了背
Five years ago, I hurt my back.
為了幫我表兄搬張該死的沙發
I was helping my cousin move a stupid couch.
醫生給我開了點兒止痛片
Doctor gave me some pain pills.
結果我欲罷不能
Turns out I liked them.
我上癮了  自己都沒覺察到
I got hooked before I even knew what was happening.
然后呢
So?
然后
So...
我在卡森泉把一個小混混
I'm chasing a gangbanger down an alley
逼到了一條巷子里  然后我的癮上來了
in Carson Springs, and I'm out of it.
完全意識不清了
I mean, way out of it.
我以為有人跟蹤我
I thought--I thought I was being followed.
我開槍打死了一個小女孩
I shot a little girl.
她十二歲
A 12-year-old girl.
當地警察采了我的血樣
Local cops took my blood.
他們有目擊證人  我當時死定了
They had witnesses. They had me cold.
然后來了個警探
And then this detective,
他找到我說
he reaches out to me and he says
他們可以把這事擺平
they can make it all go away.
然后真的擺平了
And they did.
血樣  目擊證人  都擺平了
The blood tests, the witnesses--all of it?
他們擺平那事兒以后
Hell, when they got done fixing it,
聯調局還給我頒發了一枚獎章呢
the F.B.I. gave me a medal.
"他們"到底是誰
And exactly who are "they"?
我們自稱為"布萊克組織"
We call ourselves the Blake Association.
為什么
Why?
老虎  老虎
"Tiger, tiger."
老虎  老虎  燃燒著煌煌的火光
"Tyger, tyger burning bright."
此處摘自郭沫若譯本
來自布萊克的詩作
From the poem by Blake.
大概某人很喜歡他的作品吧
Someone's a big fan of his, I guess.
組織里還有些什么人
Well, who else is in the association?
警察  法官  聯調局探員
Cops, judges, F.B.I. agents.
任何一個有秘密需要掩蓋的執法人員
Anyone in law enforcement that needs a secret covered up.
比如你的毒癮
Like your drug habit.
當你有麻煩了  向他們求助
You need a favor, you ask for it.
當他們讓你做點什么  你就得照做
You get asked to do something, you do it.
"老虎  老虎"
"Tiger, tiger."
對
Yep.
組織有頭目嗎
Well, is there somebody who's in charge?
肯定有
Must be.
但我不知道是誰
But I don't know who.
我只知道我所接觸的小團體
I just know my little group. That's it.
不過我猜測
But I'm guessing
整個組織至少有數百人  甚至上千人
there must be hundreds of us, maybe thousands.
難道就沒人發覺這一切嗎
And nobody knows about it?
鮑勃·柯克蘭知道這事  對吧
Bob Kirkland knew about it, didn't he?
快直接招了吧  說出來給你自己一個解脫
Go ahead, just say it. Unburden yourself.
是的
Yeah.
他知道的太多了
He knew too much.
所以我殺了他
So I killed him.
你知道血腥約翰
Do you know that Red John's a member
也是布萊克組織的成員嗎
of the Blake Association?
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
血腥約翰有一個追隨者
Red John had a follower.
麗貝卡·安德森
Rebecca Anderson.
四年前殺了幾個你們的人
Killed some of your guys about four years ago.
是的  山姆·博斯科和他的小隊
Yeah, Sam Bosco and his team.
就是他們
Them.
有人曾要我搞到聯調局證件
Someone asked me to get F.B.I. credentials
以便他們能進入加調局
so that they could access CBI.
血腥約翰或者他的手下
Red John or someone who worked for him
潛入加調局  對麗貝卡下毒
snuck into the CBI and poisoned Rebecca.
你竟然為他們提供了幫助
And you helped them?
那時我才知道
I mean, that's when I knew.
我是在幫助一個連環殺手
I'd--I'd done a favor for a serial killer.
是誰讓你搞那些證件的
Who asked you to get the credentials?
我不知道  我只是接到一通電話
I don't know. It was a phone call.
這就是組織的運作方式
That's the way the association works.
你永遠不知道上線是誰
You never know.
你們
You...
你們能保證我的安全 對吧
You're gonna be able to keep me safe, right?
那要看情況了
That depends.
是你殺害了我的妻子和女兒嗎
Did you murder my wife and daughter?
我沒有殺你的妻子和女兒
I did not murder your wife and daughter.
以我母親的名義起誓
I swear on my mother.
你相信他嗎
Do you believe him?
他承認了謀殺罪行
He confessed to murder.
血腥約翰絕不會這么容易崩潰
Red John would never break like that,
即便是做戲也不會如此
not even as an act.
如果史密斯不是血腥約翰
Well, if Smith isn't Red John...
那就意味著我們還得繼續追查
that means we have work to do.
我們需要幫助
And we need help.
誰是布倫達·夏垂克的繼任者
Who took over from Brenda Shettrick?
公共關系部嗎  干什么
In media relations? Why?
非常感謝大家能在臨時通知后趕來
Thank you for coming on such short notice.
這位是加調局顧問派翠克·簡
We have CBI consultant Patrick Jane here,
他將就血腥約翰一案的進展
who is here to report a development
進行通報
in the Red John case.
謝謝
Thank you.
十年前
Ten years ago,
被稱作血腥約翰的連環殺手
the serial killer known as Red John
殺害了我的妻子和女兒
killed my wife and daughter.
自那以后  我們一直在全力追捕他
Uh, we've been hunting him diligently ever since.
今天我們很高興地宣布
Today we're pleased to announce
我們終于確認了他的身份與面目
that we--we finally have a name, a face.
執法部門負責人
The director of the division of law enforcement,
蓋爾·伯特侖局長  就是血腥約翰
Gail Bertram, is Red John.
他持有武器  極度危險
He's armed and dangerous.
如果有人發現他的行蹤  切勿靠近
If you see him, do not approach him.
請立即致電加利福尼亞州調查局
Call the california Bureau of Investigation at once.
謝謝
Thank you.
請輪流提問
One question at a time.
抱歉請回避  女士
Excuse me, madam.
我們能談談這事嗎
So are we gonna talk about this?
什么事
Talk about what?
關于伯特侖是血腥約翰的事
Bertram is Red John.
看起來就是他
Looks like.
如果讓簡找到他  簡會殺了他的
And if Jane finds him, he's gonna kill him.
是啊
Yeah.
那我們就沒問題嗎  把頂頭上司殺了
And we're good with that? Killing the boss?
-我無所謂  -我也是
- I am. - Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
只要我們保持步調統一
Just as long as we're on the same page.
我就是覺得有點詭異
It's just weird, is all.
伯特侖吸煙嗎
Does Bertram smoke?
不吸吧
No, I don't think so.
有時候人們會收到打火機作為禮物
People get them as gifts sometimes.
范佩爾
Van Pelt.
是個閃存盤
A flash drive.
我們來瞧瞧
Let's take a look.
納帕谷  七仙女酒廠
盤里只有一個文件
There's only one file on the drive.
有密碼保護
It's password-protected.
我得硬破解
I'll have to brute-force it.
棒極了  我一直想用用我的新FPGA
Cool. I've been wanting to use my new F.P.G.A.
[FPGA: 現場可編程邏輯門排列]
你的什么
Your what?
相信我  還是別問了
Trust me, don't ask.
加州調查局  內部數據庫
然后
And...
進去了
we're in.
加州調查局  內部數據庫
[亂碼]
該死的
Crap.
看起來像個清單
It looks like a list.
會不會是名單  你能破譯嗎
Names, maybe? Can you decode it?
我先試試看
I can try a few things...
但破解謎題是簡的任務
But decoding is Jane's department.
我到時候發給他
I'll send it to him.
來一杯這個  這種威士忌口感很純
Here you go. This one isn't messing around.
用了很多泥煤烘烤麥芽
Lots of peat.
很不錯  能加點冰塊嗎
Yeah, that's pretty good. Can you put some rocks in it?
你確定嗎  這可是上好的蘇格蘭威士忌
Are you sure? This is some fine Scotch.
我確定
Yeah, I'm sure.
那家伙跟你有點像
That guy looks like you.
連環殺人犯
我需要一輛車
I need a ride.
我們在去酒吧的路上了
We're en route to the bar now.
高速巡警封鎖了高速公路
Highway patrol shut down the freeways,
只要他一跑我們就能抓住
so if he runs, we've got him,
但他要是躲起來怎么辦
but what if he hides?
伯特侖在柑橘高地殺了個酒保
Bertram killed the bartender in Citrus Heights.
他在那邊的姨媽有間房子
He's got an aunt with a house there.
你覺得他在那里嗎
You think that's where he is?
她六個月之前搬到養老院去了
She moved into a retirement home about six months ago,
所以她家現在空著
so her place is empty now.
聽起來是個不錯的藏身之處  地址在哪
Sounds like a good place to hide. What's the address?
露絲瑪麗街1408號
1408 Rosemary Street.
我們就到  讓周和快速反應小組過去
We're on our way. Get Cho and R.R.T. there now,
準備好直升機
and let the choppers know.
-他在這嗎  -在那里面
- Is he here? - Yes, he is. He's in there.
我讓卡爾和幾個人去后面了
I got Karl and a few guys in the back.
-他無處可逃  -我們能信他們嗎
- He's not going anywhere. - Do we trust them?
我看了他們的肩膀  沒有紋身
I asked to see their shoulders, no tattoos.
你來這里干什么  我沒叫薩城警局派特警
What are you doing here? I didn't call Sac P.D S.W.A.T.
有人要我們來的
Well, someone asked for us.
在那邊建一個指揮中心
Let's set up a command center right here!
聽著  各位  這里由我負責
Listen, everybody, I'm in charge!
他們是從北區來的
They came from northern district.
都跨了整個城了  到底是什么情況
That's way across the town. What the hell is going on?
是他干的  他把他們叫來的
He did it. He called them in.
伯特侖把特警叫到自己這來干嘛
Well, why would Bertram call S.W.A.T. to his own location?
他不止召來了一個特警組
He didn't call in one S.W.A.T. team.
他把整個特警隊都召來了
He called all of them in.
一片混亂
This is a madhouse.
屋后有整整一隊別的警察在準備
There's a whole 'nother unit setting up out back.
我們無法控制局面了  頭兒
We've lost control of the scene, boss.
他在他們之中  伯特侖混在他們之中
He's one of them. Bertram is one of them.
他要逃跑  我們得停止行動
He's getting away. We gotta shut it down.
誰都不許走
Nobody leaves!
一個人都不許走
No one leaves!
你安全了
You're clear.
我得吃點東西
I need something to eat.
要吃中餐么  我知道有一家很好吃
How about Chinese? I know a great place.
好  聽起來不錯
Yeah, sounds good.
他們在屋里發現了伯特侖的衣服
They found Bertram's clothes inside the house.
應該是有人在他去之前
Looks like someone planted a S.W.A.T. team outfit
就在房子里放好了特警服
in the house before he got there.
然后把城里所有的特警和
And then called every S.W.A.T. and
快速反應小組叫了過去
R.R.T. in the area.
知道是誰打的電話嗎
Any leads about who made all those calls?
一定是個能在暗中一呼百應的人
Somebody who could pull a lot of strings at once.
布萊克組織
Blake Association.
頭兒
Boss.
請各位注意一下
May I have your attention, please?
放下電話  離開你們的桌子
Put down your phones and step away from your desks.
馬上
Now.
我是這里特別探員主管特蕾莎·里斯本
I'm special agent in charge Teresa Lisbon.
你又是哪位
Who the hell are you?
聯調局監管部門探員  丹尼斯·阿爾伯特
F.B.I. supervisory agent Dennis Abbott.
再說一遍  站起來
Now I repeat, stand up
離開桌子
and stand away from your desks...
請了
Please.
我們正在追捕
We're in the middle of a manhunt
一名極其危險的逃犯
for a dangerous fugitive.
如果你們想協助
Now if you would like to assist--
你們這個所謂的執法部門的長官
The head of this alleged law enforcement organization
是個殺人犯
is a murderer,
還是重大犯罪組織的一員
and a member of a massive criminal conspiracy.
那個組織里也有聯調局探員
Which included F.B.I. agents.
對  所以局里把我
Yes, and that's why the bureau sent me here
從德州奧斯汀調過來
from the Austin, Texas, office.
收拾你們這個爛攤子
To clean up the mess.
我手里有一份
I am holding in my hand
聯邦法官簽署的令狀
a writ from a federal judge.
聯調局將立即關停你們部門
The F.B.I.'s closing down your organization right now.
所有人
All of you
解除任職
are relieved from your active duties
立即生效
as of this moment.
你不能這么做
You can't do that.
我是來收集證據的
I'm here to collect evidence.
不要妨礙我
Don't get in my way.
大伙開始吧
Let's go to work, fellas.
這是怎么了
What's going on here?
你的
That's yours.
我是聯調局的丹尼斯·阿爾伯特
Dennis Abbott, F.B.I.
你一定是派翠克·簡了
You must be Patrick Jane.
他們關停了我們部門
They've shut us down.
我們到時候會找你問話
We're gonna need to interview you at some point,
不過可以緩一緩  我們會在這兒待一陣子
but it can wait. We're gonna be here for some time.
別出城
Just don't leave town.
我們還有個兇手要抓
We have a killer to catch.
這案子現在歸我們管了
Oh, well, that's our problem now.
你有過機會  但是搞砸了
You had your chance to catch him and you blew it--
如果你當時是真想抓他的話
if you were really trying.
這是我最喜歡的杯子
That was my favorite cup.
好  幸會  再見了
Okay, well, see you in the funny pages.
現在怎么辦
What now?
不知道
I don't know.
范佩爾在伯特侖的閃存里找到了一些加密文件
Van Pelt found some coded files in Bertram's flash drive.
我們要不要從那開始查
Should we get started on those?
不用了  浪費時間而已  結束了
No, it's a waste of time. We're done.
這里沒我們的事兒了
There's nothing more to do here.
回家吧  休息一下
Just go home, get some rest.
你不會放棄  我不信你會放棄
You're not quitting. I don't believe it.
不  我不是放棄
No, I'm not quitting.
是放手
I'm letting go.
目前的情況我們已經無法掌控了
It's out of our hands for now.
保持聯絡  好嗎
But I'll be in touch. Okay?
所有的一切  我很抱歉
I'm sorry. For everything.